Nicolas Taconet

Current position

Since 2017 **PhD candidate in Environmental Economics**, Centre International de Recherche en Environment et Développement (CIRED), *Essays on the economic impacts of climate change*. Supervisor: C. Guivarch. Expected completion: Summer 2020.

Research interests: Integrated Assessment Modeling, Climate change, Inequality and environment, Scenario analysis.

Education

- 2017 MPP in Sustainable Development, École des Ponts ParisTech.
- 2016 MSc in Economics of Environment, Energy and Transport, École Polytechnique.
- 2014 **BSc in Advanced Engineering**, École Polytechnique.

Publications

Forthcoming Inégalités Mondiales et Changement Climatique.

with Céline Guivarch, in Numéro Spécial "Ecologie et inégalité", Revue de l'OFCE (Forthcoming January 2020)

Book chapters

Forthcoming Global inequality and climate change.

with Céline Guivarch, in Routledge Handbook of the Political Economy of the Environment (Forthcoming in 2020)

Work in progress

In revision Climate change and inequality between countries: influence of climate change impacts and

mitigation costs on inequalities in the 21st century.

with Aurélie Méjean and Céline Guivarch, Draft upon request

In revision Social Cost of Carbon under stochastic tipping points: does risk play a role?.

with Céline Guivarch and Antonin Pottier, Link to FAERE Working paper

In progress Optimal climate policy under inter and intra-generational inequalities: revisiting Schelling's

conjecture.

In progress Behavioral aspects of air travels: Evidence from France.

with Franziska Klein

In progress Impact of rate-triggered tipping points on the Social Cost of Carbon.

Work Experience

 ${\it March-July} \quad \textbf{French Ministry for the Environment}, \ Economic \ Policy \ Analyst.$

2018 Worked on socio-technical uncertainties in low carbon pathways using Dynamic Marginal Abatement Curves.

2016–2017 Agence Française de Développement, Research Assistant for the Chief Economist.

Studied carbon prices in line with Paris Agreement, using coupling between macro (GEMMES) and bottom-up (POLES) models.

March–July CIRED, Research fellow.

2016 Developed a stochastic Integrated Assessment Model using dynamic programming.

March-Aug Environmental Defense Fund, Research Assistant for G. Wagner.

2015 Literature review on Emissions Trading Systems for World Bank-led Handbook

Summer 2014 Climate Economics Chair, Research intern.

Research on environmental valuation methods and discrete choice experiments in public policy.

Oral presentations

- 2019 RSERC seminar (Berlin), FAERE (Rennes), CIRED Summer School, Journées Louis André Gérard Varet (Aix-en-Provence), AMSE Spring School (Marseille), CIRED Séminaire Doctorant.
- 2018 Journées Climat et Impact Université (Université Paris-Sud), IAMC2018 (Séville), Summer School EAERE-FEEM-VIU (Venice), International Energy Workshop (Gothenburg).
- 2016 IAMC2016 (Beijing).

Teaching

École des Ponts ParisTech.

Tutoring of students' projects Cost-benefits analysis Industrial Organization (2017-2018)

Agro ParisTech.

Integrated Assessment Models: DICE Université Sorbonne Paris Cité. Environmental Economics (2017-2018)

Miscellaneous

Languages French (native language), English (fluent), German (C2), Italian (B2)

Computer R, Python, SciLab, Stata

Volunteering public writer, tutoring in prisons (GENEPI)

Hobbies Sports and cinema